PJ  我这里有好消息也有坏消息
P.J., I got good news and bad news.
是吗  坏消息是什么
Okay, what's the bad news?
该到老爸一年一度的钓鱼之旅了
It's time for the annual fishing trip with dad.
那好消息又是什么
What's the good news?
今年轮到你去了
It's your turn to go.
什么  等等
What? Hold on.
我去年去过了  今年轮到你了
I went last year. It's your turn to go.
没错  但是当你离开这个家后
Yeah, but when you're out of the house,
每年都会是我去了
I'll be the one going every year.
别装了  人人都知道我不会离开的
Come on, everyone knows I'm never leaving.
我就是受不了老爸每年都讲一样的冷笑话
Just can't hear that same stupid joke dad tells every year.
你是说上次他放屁后
You mean the one where he passes gas
然后说了句“嘿  我又不知道这是艘汽艇”
and goes, "hey, I didn't know this was a motorboat"?
嘿  小伙子们  今年谁想和我一起去钓鱼啊
Hey, boys, who wants to go fishing with dad?
-他想  -他想
-He does. -He does.
告诉你们吧  你们也不用争了
You know what? You can quit your arguing.
因为我今年租了艘大船  你们都可以去
'Cause this year I rented a bigger boat. You both get to go.
-好耶  -好耶
-Yay. -Yay.
我只希望这回不是汽艇
I just hope it ain't a motorboat.
生活搞得一团糟
<i>Today's all burnt toast </i>
■
本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献
欢迎登录 www.Deefun.com
就要迟到  爸爸在叫
<i>Running late, and dad jokes</i>
我左脚的鞋子有没有人看到
<i>Has anybody seen my left shoe</i>
■
翻译： Johnny-Z
我闭上眼  咬口早餐
<i>I close my eyes, take a bite</i>
跳上车子  放声大笑
<i>Grab a ride, laugh out loud</i>
哎呀  老爸  鞋子就在房顶上
<i>There it is up on the roof</i>
■
校订： line
我也曾这样生活  我已经顺利走过
<i>I've been there, I've survived</i>
所以听取我的建议
<i>So just take my advice</i>
■
后期： Johnny-Z  liloelva
宝贝  不要放弃
<i>Hang in there, baby</i>
世界有很多疯狂无奈
<i>Things are crazy</i>
可是我知道你会有美好将来
<i>But I know your future's bright</i>
宝贝  不要放弃
<i>Hang in there, baby</i>
不要怀疑
<i>There's no maybe</i>
一切终会如你所愿
<i>Everything turns out all right</i>
生活有悲有喜
<i>Your life is up and down</i>
但是请相信我  坚持就有好结果
<i>But trust me it comes back around</i>
你会喜欢将来的你
<i>You're gonna love</i> <i>who you turn out to be</i>
宝贝  不要放弃
<i>Hang in there, baby.</i>
查莉成长日记  第二季第二十集
Good Luck Charlie  S02E20  Amazing Gracie
“你第四题选什么”
"what did you get for number four?"
你干吗不直接看我的卷子
Why didn't you just look at my paper?
那样算作弊
That would be cheating.
如果改为发短信  可以认为是朋友互助
If I text, it's just friends hanging out.
你居然花了整个周末来陪她  哈里
You spent the whole weekend with her, Harry.
-我应该回避下吗  -他们天天这么吵
-Should I leave? -They have this fight all the time.
你应该回家来陪自己的老婆
You should be home with your wife.
而不是在外面对她用降龙十八摸
Not out there with your hands all over her.
她叫格雷西
Her name is Gracie.
抱歉  我听不下去了
I'm sorry. I can't just hear and listen to this.
你俩一定要把这件事解决了
You two need to work this out.
现在不论格雷西是谁
Now whoever this Gracie is...
-她是辆车  -是车啊
-She's a car. -She's a car.
当然是辆车了
Of course she's a car.
很高兴能帮助你们
I'm so glad I could help.
她是辆旧车
She's an old car
还占了我的车库位置
That's taking my spot in the garage.
你什么时候才能把那破车给我扔了
When are you gonna get rid of that thing?
我不会把我的心肝宝贝卖给陌生人的
I am not selling my baby to some stranger.
其实  我最近是想买辆车
Actually, I've been thinking about buying a car.
听见了吗  哈里
Do you hear that, Harry?
我不是很了解她
I don't know her that well.
噢  别这样  她也可以算是家庭中的一份子了
Oh, come on, she's practically family.
那么
Well...
我会考虑下的
I guess I could consider it.
-泰迪  你想见见格雷西吗  -好啊
-Teddy, would you like to meet Grace? -Sure.
你洗完手后  我再带你去
I'll take you right out as soon as you wash your hands.
明天注定不好过啊
Tomorrow is gonna be such a tough day.
那还用说
It sure is.
你不知道明天有什么事  对吧
You have no idea what tomorrow is, do you?
不知道  女士  还真不知道
No, ma'am, I do not.
明天是查莉的幼儿园第一天
It's Charlie's first day of preschool.
但是我一点也高兴不起来
And I'm not looking forward to it
因为我知道她一定会又哭又闹的
Because she's gonna be crying and screaming
然后像其他孩子一样  抓住我的腿不放
and grabbing onto my legs like all the kids did.
亲爱的  如果你乐意  我去送她
Honey, if you want, I'll take her.
难道你想让我错过这一切吗  你疯了吗
And miss all that? Are you crazy?
嘿  老爸老妈  能和你们说点事吗
Hey, mom, dad, can I talk to you guys for a sec?
可以  宝贝  什么事
Sure, honey, what's up?
听着  艾薇的爸爸想向我出售他的车
Okay, so Ivy's dad has offered to sell me his car.
而我想向你们贷点儿款
And I'd like to ask for you guys to loan me the money.
-好啊  -在你们拒绝我之前
-Sure. -Now before you say no,
我弄了一份资料  等等  你们说什么
I made this presentation and... wait. What?
我们说可以
We said okay.
这个  我花了很长的时间来整合这些资料
'Cause the thing is, I spent a lot of time putting this presentation together
所以我很希望来展示一下
so I'd really like to present it.
亲娘啊
Goodness gracious,
-有很多曲线图和图表啊  -没错
-there's lots of graphs and charts. -Yes.
如果你放我们走  我会再额外给你多加五十块钱
I'll give you an extra 50 bucks if we can leave now.
展示到此结束  好了
That concludes our presentation. Okay.
好了  我们到了
Okay, here we go.
第一天啊
It's the first day.
不好过啊
It's not gonna be pretty.
好了  现在
Okay, now...
妈妈需要你勇敢起来  好吗
Mommy needs you to be brave, okay?
我保证会尽快接你回家的
And I promise I'm gonna come back real soon to pick you up,
-好吗  -好的
-Okay? -Okay.
来个拥抱
Big hugs.
挺轻松的
That was easy.
我为这么轻松而感到好开心啊
I'm so happy that was so easy.
-你怎么了  -扭伤了胳膊  不能去钓鱼了
-What happened to you? -Sprained my arm so I can't go fishing.
你又是怎么了
What happened to you?
扭伤了眼睛
Sprained my eye.
-噢  算了吧  -蒙不过去的
-Aw, forget it. -This isn't gonna work.
为什么我们非要去钓鱼
Why do we always have to go fishing?
为什么老爸不和他的朋友去
Why can't dad go with one of his friends?
等一下
Wait a minute.
你刚才说的话有点意思
You just said something really interesting.
是吗  该死  我刚才真应该仔细听听
I did? Oh shoot. Now I wish I had been listening.
如果我们让老爸的朋友和他去钓鱼
If we can get dad to take some of his friends fishing,
那咱们就不用去了
then we don't have to go.
没错  好了  谁是老爸的朋友
You're right. Okay, who are dad's friends?
他没有朋友
He doesn't have any.
-确定吗  -想想看
-Are you sure? -Think about it.
当有人来敲门后
Have youver answered the door
你说过“老爸  你朋友来了”这句话吗
and said, "dad, your friends are here?"
所以我们的任务就是给老爸找一个朋友
So all we gotta do is find dad a friend.
你是说给老爸找朋友
You mean like fix him up?
没错  我们要给他找个伴儿
That's right. We gotta get dad a dude.
好了
Well...
该道别了
I guess this is goodbye.
温茨先生
Mr. Wentz,
你想一个人呆会吗
would you like a moment alone?
他昨晚在后座上睡的觉
He slept in the back seat last night.
我只是想确认下您是否真的想这么做
I just wanna make sure that you really wanna do this.
想卖掉自己的车吗
So you really wanna sell your car?
-这个  -他会把车卖了的
-Well... -<i>He's selling the car!</i>
泰迪  在你走之前
Teddy, before you go,
你能帮我和我的心肝宝贝合张影吗
would you take a picture of me and my special girl?
好的
Sure.
我是指格雷西
I meant Gracie.
那是当然了
Of course you did.
嘿  亲爱的  查莉的第一天如何啊
Hey, honey, how'd Charlie's first day of school go?
悲剧
Awful.
不会吧  怎么了  她又哭又闹了
Oh no, what happened? She make a scene?
没有  没哭没闹  她只是径直走进那扇门
No, she didn't. She just walked through the door
连头都不回一下
without a care in the world.
哪里悲剧了
What was the awful part?
刚才说的不就是嘛
I just told you.
但我知道问题出在哪里
But I know what the problem is.
没错  查莉是第四个孩子
Mm-hmm. Charlie is the fourth child.
我没有花足够的时间来陪她
So I didn't get to spend enough time with her.
所以我们之间的感情不够深
We did not get enough bonding.
好吧  更深的感情
Okay, so with more bonding,
带来的是她和你在学校分别的时候会大哭大闹
then she'll cry when you drop her off at school,
这就是好事了吗
and that's a good thing?
没错
Yes.
好了  请你跟住我的节奏
Okay, try and stay with me, Bob.
你今天反映有些迟钝
You seem a little slow today.
嘿  大家  我看见泰迪刚把她的新车停下来
Hey guys, I think Teddy just pulled up in her new car.
-去围观下  -好的
-Let's go check it out. -Yeah.
看起来很明显吗
Is it noticeable?
噢  宝贝  你还好吧
Oh, honey. Are you okay?
-没事  我很好  -那好  发生了什么
-Yeah, no, I'm fine. -Well, what happened?
在回家的路上  有只松鼠在路中间
I was driving home and in the middle of the road there was this squirrel.
于是你就来了个急转弯  然后就撞上什么东西了
So you swerved to avoid it and you hit something?
不是  我停下来然后鸣笛了
No, I stopped and I honked.
然后什么东西撞到你了
So then someone hit you?
我是故事的主人公  让我说完  成吗
This is my accident. Let me tell it.
总之  我下了车想赶走它
Anyway, I got out of my car and I tried to Chase it off,
但是它被一大块口香糖给粘住了
but it was stuck to this huge wad of gum.
什么口味的口香糖
What flavor?
谁管这个
Who cares?
和你说下  回到早些时候的那个话题
By the way, to get back to the earlier conversation,
你和PJ的感情最深
P.J. Had the most bonding time.
总之  当我盯着那只松鼠时
Anyway, while I was staring at the squirrel,
一辆垃圾车正从一条小巷里往外倒车
a garbage truck was backing out of an alley
然后径直撞向了我的车
and it smashed right into the car.
你觉着还能修理吗
Do you think it can be fixed?
宝贝  恐怕花那么多的钞票
Honey, I'm afraid it's gonna cost more
不值得修理这辆车
to fix than the car is worth.
太悲剧了
This is awful.
不知道当温茨先生发现后会怎么说
What's Mr. Wentz gonna say when he finds out?
心肝宝贝
Baby!
我打赌他说的是心肝宝贝
I bet he says baby.
嘿
Hey!
我好朋友吉米的爸爸来接他回家了
It's my friend Jimmy's dad here to pick up my friend Jimmy.
请进  和我爸爸打声招呼
Come in, say hi to my dad.
-嗨  我是马克  -鲍伯
-Hi, I'm Mark. -Bob.
我就知道你俩合得来
I knew you guys would hit it off.
你是吉米的爸爸
So you're Jimmy's dad?
是的
Yeah.
那你是盖比的爸爸
And your Gabe's.
看看你们有多少共同点啊
What don't you guys have in common?
吉米呢
So where is Jimmy?
老爸  拜托  我们正在招呼吉米的爸爸呢
Dad, please, we're focusing on Jimmy's dad.
吉米的爸爸也想知道吉米在哪
Who is also wondering where Jimmy is.
同志们  别提吉米了
Guys, enough with the Jimmy.
除了吉米还有很多事情可以谈啊
There are other things to talk about besides Jimmy,
比如钓鱼啊  我知道你俩都喜欢这项运动
like fishing, which I know you both love.
别提我  我可不擅长室外运动
Not me. I can't do anything outdoorsy.
-过敏  -噢
-Allergies. -Oh.
真希望吉米能在之前告诉我过敏这事
Sure wish Jimmy would mentioned that in the pre-interview.
嘿  噢  抱歉  老爸  我不知道你有客人
Hey... oh, sorry. Dad, I didn't realize you had company.
把你的人带进来吧  我的人失败了
Bring your guy in. My guy's not working out.
我记得吉米一小时之前就走了
I just remembered Jimmy left about an hour ago.
再见了
Bye-bye.
老爸  我极力推荐给你一个人认识
Dad, there's somebody I am dying for you to meet.
这位是  你叫什么来着
This is... what's your name again?
-罗杰  -没错
-Roger. -Right.
罗杰  这是我老爸  鲍伯
Roger, this is my dad Bob.
-你好啊  -嘿
-How you doing? -Hey.
告诉我老爸你刚才点了什么  老爸  听好了
Tell my dad what you just ordered. Dad, wait'll you hear this.
这绝对让你血脉喷张
This is going to blow your mind.
咕唧鱼拼盘
The kwikki fishy combo.
一个到炸鸡店买鱼的人
The guy comes into a chicken place and orders fish.
他喜欢鱼  你喜欢钓鱼
He loves fish. You love to fish.
罗杰  鲍伯  你俩绝配啊
Roger, Bob, perfect together.
其实  我是为了我的老婆而买鱼
Actually, I ordered the fish for my wife.
我讨厌鱼
I hate fish.
鄙视你
Tease.
好了  走吧
All right, come on, let's go.
盖比  你们搞什么
Gabe, what is going on?
你最好不要这么挑剔了  先生
What's going on is you better stop being so fussy, mister,
不然你会孤独终老的
or you're gonna end up alone.
好了  查莉  想开心一下吗
Okay, Charlie, are you ready to have some fun?
因为今天是母女亲情日
Because today is mommy and Charlie day.
耶
Yay!
好了  咱们再试一遍
Okay, let's try that again.
今天是母女亲情日
Today is mommy and Charlie day.
耶
Yay!
天啊  我们有的忙了
Boy, we got some work to do.
听着  我们来玩这个
All right, here's what we're gonna do.
捉迷藏怎么样
We're gonna play hide and seek, okay?
捂住你的眼睛  然后数到十
Cover your eyes and count to 10.
一  二  我来了
One, two... here we come.
哈  被你发现了
Ahh, you found me.
他的农场里有只鸭
On his farm he had a duck
咿呀咿呀噢  在这里嘎嘎叫
E-I-e-I-o! With a quack quack here
在那里嘎嘎叫  这里嘎  那里嘎
And a quack quack there, here a quack, there a quack
到处嘎嘎叫  老麦当劳有个农场
Everywhere a quack quack, old MacDonald had a farm
咿呀咿呀噢
E-I-e-I-o!
多美好的一天啊
What a day.
呜
Ooh!
我们欢笑  我们玩耍
We laughed. We played.
我们唱歌
We sang.
你明天一定会哭出来的
You are so gonna cry tomorrow.
大家看看是谁起床了
Look who got out of bed, everybody.
-嗨  温茨先生  -你好啊  泰迪
-Hi, Mr. Wentz. -Hello, Teddy.
你好  艾薇  你好玛丽·卢
Hello, Ivy. Hello, Mary Lou.
亲爱的  在楼上
Honey, we said our hellos
我们已经打过招呼了  还记得吗
at the top of the stairs, remember?
没错  没错
Right right.
我过来看看您是否还好
I came by to see how you're doing
然后再说一遍
and to say again,
对于格雷西的遭遇我深表抱歉
I'm so sorry about Gracie.
没事了  泰迪
That's okay, Teddy.
我想是她的阳寿已尽
I guess it was just her time.
我只是想有个机会和她说声再见
I just wish I had a chance to say goodbye.
你好  玛丽·卢
Hello, Mary Lou.
知道了  给你沏杯茶吧  好吗
Okay, let's get you a cup of tea, okay?
-过来  -再见
-Come on. -Bye.
-哇  -是啊
-Wow. -Yeah.
这太惨了
This is awful.
真希望我可以帮上一些忙
I wish there was some way I could help him.
嘿  你爸爸说他只想说声再见  对吧
Hey, your dad said that he just wanted to say goodbye, right?
-没错  -那么说来他需要的是一场追悼会
-Right. -So he just needs closure.
我有办法了
I know how to do that.
天啊  透过你的眼睛  我看到了疯狂的眼神
Uh-oh. You got that crazy look in your eye.
不  这一点也不疯狂  绝对正常  绝对管用
No, this isn't crazy at all. This is good. This could work.
你父亲和这辆车有没有首特别之歌
Did your dad and the car have a special song?
好了  第二天了
Okay, day number two.
也不简单啊
Not gonna be easy.
好了  查莉  昨天我们玩得很高兴  对吧
All right, Charlie, we had a lot of fun yesterday, didn't we?
是的  很高兴
Yeah, we did.
所以今天对于你来说不怎么好过  对吧
So today's gonna be really hard for you, okay?
你可能会想哭
You might wanna cry.
没关系的  尽管哭好了
It's okay. It's okay if you wanna cry.
我就是一个小丑
But I was the Jack in the box.
这才是我的乖宝宝
That's my baby.
看见了吗  她就是不肯放手
See that? She can't let go.
噢  嘿  老爸
Oh hey, dad.
呃  什么情况
Um... what's this?
我们召集了一些来自比利鱼饵店和钓具店的人过来
We're just having a little mixer with the guys from Billy's bait and tackle shop.
没错  给你  倒杯饮料
Yeah, here, grab a drink.
融入这个圈子  别害羞
Mingle. Don't be shy.
成了  你俩给我去厨房
Okay, you two in the kitchen now.
我们马上回来
We'll be right back.
如果你们饿了  那里有鱼味饼干和美味虫子
If you guys get hungry, there are fish crackers and yummy worms.
还有水  淡水和盐水
Water, fresh or salt.
好了  到底怎么回事
All right, what's going on?
-没事  -我们只是想开个鱼饵商店派对
-Nothing. -Just a couple kids having a bait shop party.
仅此而已
That's all.
你们两个不想和我一起去钓鱼  是吧
You guys don't wanna go fishing with me, do you?
我是想和你去的啊
Well, I wanna go fishing with you.
-你才不想去呢  -对  我不想去
-No, you don't. -No, I really don't.
难道你们以为我让你们去钓鱼
Do you think when I ask you to go fishing,
只是因为我喜欢钓鱼吗
it's 'cause I wanna go fishing?
小心了  听起来像是个脑筋急转弯
Careful. This has all the signs of a trick question.
儿子们啊  我只想多陪陪我的孩子们
Guys, I just wanna spend time with my sons.
我才不在乎去干什么
I don't care what we do,
只要我们可以在一起
just so long we do it together.
那我们可以做除了钓鱼的事情吗
So we can do something else besides fishing?
同志们  我们可以做的事情有很多
Guys, there's all sorts of things we can do.
我们可以打高尔夫球
We can go golfing.
打保龄球  看电影  我不在乎做什么
We can go bowling. We can go to the movies. I don't care.
-我选电影  -我也是
-I vote for the movies. -Yeah.
但是我们不和你挨着
But we're not sitting with you.
为什么
Why not?
你知道自己吃完爆米花后的所作所为
Well, you know how popcorn affects your stomach?
然后你就开始讲那个笑话
And then you make that joke,
“这部电影拍的一定很臭”
"this movie must be rated p.U."
每个地方都有对应的笑话
I got one for every venue.
好了  好了  我们马上开始了  大家
Okay, all right, we're gonna get started, everyone.
我首先要感谢大家的到来
I'd like to thank you all for coming and joining us
庆祝一段生命的终结
for a celebration of the life
她就是格雷西·温茨
of Gracie Wentz.
到场的嘉宾有
Now there's so many people here
很多深爱着格雷西的  家人  朋友
that loved gracie... her family, her friends,
罗伊汽车制造商的罗伊
Roy from Roy's automotive.
我了解你现在的心情
I know. I know.
对格雷西我能说些什么呢
What can I say about Gracie?
她的一位奉献者
She was a giver.
实际上  是她牺牲了自己
In fact, she gave her life
那只松鼠才得以生存
so that a squirrel could live.
不幸的是  那只松鼠今天不能到场
Now unfortunately, that squirrel couldn't be with us today,
如果它能到场  我知道它会说
but if it could, I know it would say...
“谢谢你”
"Thank you."
大家还有什么关于格雷西的回忆可以分享吗
Does anyone else have any memories they would like to share of Gracie?
艾薇
Ivy.
加油  宝贝  你能行的
Come on, sweetie. You got it.
我想到的第一个关于格雷西的回忆是
My first memory of Gracie
当我五岁那年
was when I was five years old.
我们在车库里  然后爸爸说
We were in the garage and dad said,
“别碰那车”
"don't touch the car."
没错  他就是这么说的
That's right. He did.
我七岁那年
Then when I was seven,
爸爸洗车的时候  他对我说
dad was washing her and he said to me,
“别碰那车”
"don't touch the car."
-当我差不多九岁的时候  -噢  噢  噢
-Then when I was around nine... -Oh oh oh,
我认为艾薇想说的是
I-I think what Ivy is trying to say
即使她从未碰过那辆车
is that even though she never touched the car,
对吧  但是那辆车却让她深受感动
right? The car touched her.
不对  我的意思是说我从不被允许碰那辆车
No, I'm saying I wasn't allowed to touch the car.
好了  艾薇  我觉着你说的差不多了
Okay, Ivy, I think you're done.
现在  玛丽·卢·温茨太太想献上一曲
Now Mary Lou Wentz would like to dedicate a song
送给已逝的格雷西
to the memory of the dear departed Gracie.
天赐格雷西
Amazing Gracie
注：改编版Amazing Grace
多么迷人的一辆车  哈里卖给了小泰
How sweet the car that Harry sold to T
她为了一只松鼠而毁掉了车
She smashed it up to save a squirrel
如今她十分抱歉
And now she is so sorry.
礼拜仪式结束了  什么
And that concludes our service. What?
读读这个  谢谢
Read this for me. Thank you.
很显然  这场表演的光盘
Apparently, C.D.S of this performance
可以在厨房购买
will be available for purchase in the kitchen.
好了  查莉  这个星期对咱俩都意义非凡
Well, Charlie, we both hit big milestones this week.
你开始上幼儿园了  而我有了辆车
You started preschool and I got my first car.
悲剧的是  我的车只开了
Unfortunately, my milestone only lasted...
一英里
A mile.
总之  学会独立是件好事
Anyway, turns out you very independent which is a good thing.
并不是所有邓肯家的孩子都这么容易学会独立
not all Duncan kids let go so easily.
再来一遍  再来一遍
Do it again. Do it again.
当然了  宝贝
Of course I will, honey.
看够了吗  反正我看够了
Seen enough? I know I have.
祝你好运了  查莉
Good luck, Charlie.
哇
Whoa!
噢  这白干酪真是够味儿
Oh, that cottage cheese is funk-ay.
永别啦
Time to say goodbye.
噢  当奶酪
Oh, when the cheese
变味儿后
Smells really bad
噢   当奶酪
Oh, when the cheese
变味儿后
Smells really bad
噢  是时候将它倒掉
Oh, it is time to dump it out
换成一杯酸奶
And have a cup of yogurt instead.
噢  但是我  我不想要酸奶
Oh, but I... I don't want yogurt.
-她只想要奶酪  -白干酪
-She just wants cheese -Cottage cheese
-她说的是白干酪  -白干酪
-She said cottage cheese -Cottage cheese
因为我早些时候喝过酸奶了
It's because I had yogurt earlier
你为什么不能等到
Why don't you just wait
晚饭
Till dinner?
因为我现在需要一些零食
'Cause I need a snack right now
她需要零食
She needs a snack!
我需要零食
I need a snack!
零食时刻
Snack time!
耶  耶
Yeah! Yeah!
我需要零食
I need a snack
耶
Yeah
噢  噢  零食时刻
Ooh-oh, snack time
Oh! Oh! It's snack time
耶  零食
Yeah, snack
零食时刻
Snack time!
噢  噢  噢  噢  噢
Oh oh oh oh oh.